

Michael Koch

With over three years of exceptional software development experience, I bring a proven track record of continuous learning and a versatile skillset, enabling me to make an immediate impact and add value from day one. My strong interpersonal and collaborative skills allow me to effectively collaborate with team members, facilitate discussions on project requirements, and assume leadership roles in ensuring the successful deliver of projects.



856-404-8845



mkoch@michaelgkoch.com



<u>linkedin.com/in/michaelgkochh</u>



@MichaelKochDev

Website:

michaelgkoch.com

SKILLS:

JavaScript Java React C# SQL

•••

Professional Experience

November 2023 - Present

Founder @ Dream Oracles

As the Founder of Dream Oracles (dreamoracles.co), my responsibilities include:

- Engaging with Large Language Models (LLMs) to interpret symbols found in users' dreams
- Serving as the primary developer, responsible for both introducing new features and addressing software issues
- Generating innovative ideas independently, as well as incorporating feedback and suggestions from users to enhance functionality and resolve bugs
- Leveraging social media platforms and SEO strategies to attract new users
- Designing and implementing a secure database from scratch, aimed at storing users' profiles, their dreams, and the associated interpretations

Experience: NextJS 14, Tailwind CSS, MongoDB, APIs, AI (LLMs), Firebase, SEO, SMM

March 2023 – Present

Associate Software Engineer @ JP Morgan Chase

As an Associate Software Engineer for JP Morgan Chase, I am responsible for:

- Acting as Lead Front-End Developer by overseeing and producing all aspects related to user interface development.
- $\mbox{Accomplishing implementation upgrades to our UI, enabling users to perform more accurate data updates.}$
- Streamlining testing processes within our application, leading to more robust code coverage and efficient deployments
- Development of sophisticated automated functional tests to ensure proper integration and performance between our UI and API
- Maintenance of our CI/CD pipelines, resulting in effective deployments to production **Experience**: React, Spring Boot, CI/CD, Junit, SQL, AWS, TDD, Agile, APIs

May 2021 – March 2023

Software Developer @ CCLR

As a Software Developer for CCLR, I am responsible for:

- Managing the automation and interconnection of multiple departments, leading to enhanced productivity and reduced human error.
- Expanding revenue streams by performing R&D on hand-serving automation.
- Developing complex SQL queries of business data, while concurrently building an intuitive user interface for data visualization and manipulation
- Collaborating with management and employees to define business requirements, and subsequentially deliver successfully on said requirements

Experience: JavaScript, ASP.NET, C#, jQuery, SQL, HTML

June 2020 – August 2020

Web Development Intern @ Maxeta Technologies Inc.

As a Web Development Intern for Maxeta Technologies Inc., I am responsible for:

- Working with clients to outline and understand business problems.
- Helping develop an application that automates day-to-day tasks of client's employees, improving efficiency and organization company-wide.

Experience: Typescript, Angular

Education

2017 - 2021 - Philadelphia

Temple University

BS In Computer Engineering & Minor in Computer Science

Started by studying computer engineering because of my fascination with computers, but as I learned about both the hardware and software aspect of computers, I inevitably learned that software development was where my deeper interest lied, and quickly picked up an additional minor in computer science.

2022 – Online

Coursera

Machine Learning/AI Fundamentals